# **Gregory Kondas**

gkondas.github.io Email: gkondas@umich.edu

#### RESEARCH INTERESTS

My primary research interests lie at the intersection of machine learning and computational healthcare. I am broadly interested in representation learning and particularly interested in developing novel self-supervision techniques for Electronic Health Record foundation models.

• Topics: Machine Learning, Healthcare, Representation Learning, Foundation Models, Self-Supervised Learning

#### **EDUCATION**

## University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI

May 2024

- Bachelor of Science, Computer Science; Minor in Physics
- GPA: 3.94

**Relevant Courses:** Machine Learning, Computer Vision, Natural Language Processing, Linear Algebra, Structural Biology, Modern Physics, Organic/Physical/Biological Chemistry, Statistics

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Machine Learning for Data Driven Decisions Lab, Research Assistant, full-time

May 2024 - Present

• Currently working towards building novel self-supervised techniques for electronic health record data.

# Machine Learning for Data Driven Decisions Lab, Undergrad Research Assistant

May 2023 - May 2024

- Work with PhD candidate Sarah Jabbour and Professor Jenna Wiens on machine learning for healthcare.
- Second authorship on DEPICT manuscript accepted to ECCV 2024.

# Physics for the Life Sciences II, U of Michigan, Teaching Assistant

Jun. 2021 – Dec. 2023

- Articulated abstract procedures to analyze, understand, and solve physics problems with students 1-on-1.
- Facilitate two weekly problem-solving workshop sessions with ~40 students to prepare students for exams.

## Yang Lab, U of Michigan, Undergrad Research Assistant

Sep. 2021 – May 2022

- Worked on a project studying mechanical forces involved in zebra fish cell differentiation with Professor Qiong Yang and PhD student Usha Kadiyala.
- Regularly performed various wet lab tasks such as solution making, dissections, and single cell microinjection.

## ATLAS Collaboration Project, U of Michigan, Undergrad Research Assistant

Jun. 2021 – Aug. 2021

- Optimized construction and testing process of sMDTs (small Monitor Drift Tubes) for CERN's upgrade of the Muon Spectrometer at the Large Hadron Collider in Geneva, Switzerland.
- Troubleshooted / solved mechanical problems encountered during construction and testing process.

# Computational Neuroscience Lab, U of Michigan, Undergrad Research Assistant

Sep. 2020 – May 2022

- Designed and implemented median absolute deviation script in python to regularly process ~280 participant's behavioral and background data.
- Designed and implemented a pipeline to analyze heterogeneous fMRI data among MiND study participants.

# **PUBLICATIONS**

Sarah Jabbour, **Gregory Kondas**, Ella Kazerooni, Michael W. Sjoding, David Fouhey\*, Jenna Wiens\*. "DEPICT: Diffusion Enabled Permutation Importance for Image Classification Tasks." *ECCV* 2024

### **AWARDS**

Phi Beta Kappa – University of Michigan, College of Literature Science and The Arts

Apr. 2023

• Fewer than 10% of seniors are invited to join the nation's oldest academic honor society.

# **Barnstorm Freshman Prize** – University of Michigan

Mar. 2020

• Awarded to freshmen who rank in the top 5% of their class within their school or college.

## Eagle Scout - Boy Scouts of America, Cleveland, OH

2015

- Designed and facilitated construction of butterfly garden at St. Michael School in Independence, OH.
- Raised ~\$2000 in fund raising for butterfly garden materials and supplies.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

• Programming Languages: Python, C++, SQL, Java